Sanjeevan Thangaraj

Phone: 9502965479 Email: sanjeevan1122003@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/sanjeevan-thangaraj-51b70928a/

Dedicated Full stack developer with over two years of experience in front-end development and an additional year focused on backend functionality. Proficient in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python, and SQL. Enthusiastic about building user-friendly applications that balance aesthetic appeal with functional depth.

EDUCATION

SUMMARY

Priyadharshini Engineering College

Aug 2021 - presuming Grade: 8.3 CGPA

Bachelor of Technology

Jun 2019 - May 2021

Narayana Junior College

Grade: 785 Marks

Ratnam High School

Intermediate (MPC)

Jun 2017 - May 2019

Secondary School Certificate (SSC)

Grade: 8.3 CGPA

EXPERIENCE

Freelance

Aug 2022 - Present

Front-End Developer

• Developed and maintained responsive websites using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.

- Collaborated with clients to understand requirements and deliver user-centric solutions.
- Optimized website performance and ensure cross-browser compatibility.

Freelance Sep 2023-present

Backend Developer

• Developed backend functionality using Python, JavaScript and Node.js.

- Managed user credentials and ensured secure data handling using SQL.
- Integrated APIs and handled server-side logic for web applications using Express.js.

PROJECTS

Portfolio (link: https://portfolio.sanjeevantech.com/)

Aug 2024 - Sep 2024

Personal

- Designed and developed a Portfolio website using HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, and JavaScript.
- Implemented responsive design principles to ensure compatibility across devices.
- Enhanced user experience by using the Flexbox technology. And experience in responsive development.

Clone Webpage (link: https://clonewebpage.ccbp.tech/)

Oct 2024 - Nov 2024

NXTWAVE

- Designed and developed a Clone Web Page using HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, and JavaScript.
- Implemented responsive design principles to ensure compatibility across devices.
- Enhanced user experience by using the Flexbox technology.

Resume Maker Website (Developing...)

Dec 2024 - Present

Personal

- Designed and developed a resume maker website using HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, Node.js, and Express.js
- Implemented responsive design principles to ensure compatibility across devices.
- Enhanced user experience by integrating interactive features and dynamic form generation.
- · Managed user credentials and ensured secure data handling using SQL.

CERTIFICATIONS

Static website course completion (NXTWAVE)
Responsive website development course completion (NXTWAVE)
Dynamic website development course competition (NXTWAVE)
AWS Certification for hosting the static website (NXTWAVE)

SKILLS

- Programming Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python, SQL, Node.js, Express.js
- Frontend Frameworks and Libraries: Bootstrap
- Backend Development: Python, JavaScript, Node.js, Express.js
- Database Management: SQLData Visualization: Power BI
- Cloud and Web Hosting: AWS S3, CloudFront, Route 53, Render
- Soft Skills: Adaptability, Teamwork, Creative Thinking, Good Communication, Time Management